A Guide to the Old Dominion University Literary Festival, 1978-
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Old Dominion University Literary Festival 1978-
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
RG 17-3A1
5.7 Linear Feet. 1 box, 1 Hollinger Flip-top box, 1 Hollinger VHS-C box, 6 Hollinger VHS boxes, 7 Hollinger CD boxes
Old Dominion University
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The materials in the literary festival collection are available for use in research, teaching, and private study. For these purposes, you may link to or use materials from the Literary Festival website without prior permission, on the condition that you provide a citation to the original source (Old Dominion University Libraries, Annual Literary Festival Web site: http://www.lib.odu.edu/litfest/).
Acquisition Information
Original materials were donated by Philip Raisor. Additional materials were donated by James McNally, Michael Pearson, Tim Seibles, and other members of the ODU English Department. Materials are donated annually by the ODU Literary Festival committee and the ODU English Department.
Historical Information
In April 1978, the English Department held a Poetry Jam, featuring Richard Wilbur, W. D. Snodgrass, and Dave Smith. The success of the Poetry Jam and the recent explosion of community interest in the literary, visual, and performing arts in Hampton Roads, led to the First Annual Literary Festival. It was called The Arts Reunion, and it coincided with the arrival of the Associated Writing Programs' national headquarters, the birth of ODU's creative writing program, and the establishment of a Distinguished Visiting Writer position (W. D. Snodgrass was our first). It was a heady time.
The enthusiasm has continued, sustained by ever-increasing university and community support. Each October the Hampton Roads, as well as the University, calendar reminds us that for about a week our area will be home to such writers as Robert Pinsky, Rita Dove, John McPhee, William Styron, Ann Beattie, Charles Johnson, Derek Walcott, and Gwendolyn Brooks.
The diversity of readers, panels, workshops, and community involvement is one of the Festival hallmarks. Every two years the Festival is redesigned by a different English department member. The themes change from year to year. Major writers, cultural diversity, international perspectives, and numerous other approaches have surprised increasingly sophisticated audiences.
Over the years, students from Old Dominion University, surrounding campuses, and high schools have been encouraged to attend the literary events. Few, around the country, have an opportunity to hear and mingle with so many major and aspiring writers. Since Hampton Roads is a reader friendly environment, the Festival has consistently attracted patrons of bookstores, libraries, museums, and arts events.
Many of the events have been recorded. Brochures and posters (provided by the University Publications Department), news articles, interviews, and reviews are now housed in the University Archives of the University's Perry Library. Future material will also be collected there.
Because of the importance of this annual event to the university and the community, the Library and English Department have collaborated to preserve and exhibit Festival materials through the Literary Festival Digital Project.
-- Phil Raisor (English Department) and Karen Vaughan (Library)
Chronology:
Poetry Jam, April 1978
First Annual Arts Reunion, September 25-29, 1978
Second Annual Literary Festival, October 1-4, 1979
Third Annual Literary Festival, September 29 - October 1, 1980
Fourth Annual Literary Festival, October 5-8, 1981
Fifth Annual Literary Festival, October 4-7, 1982
Sixth Annual Literary Festival, October 3-6, 1983
Seventh Annual Literary Festival, October 1-4, 1984
Eighth Annual Literary Festival, October 7-10, 1985
Ninth Annual Literary Festival, October 6-9, 1986
Tenth Annual Literary Festival, October 4-8, 1987
Eleventh Annual Literary Festival, October 3-6, 1988
Twelfth Annual Literary Festival, October 2-5, 1989
Thirteenth Annual Literary Festival: City of Words, October 2-4, 1990
Fourteenth Annual Literary Festival: Between the Lines. Fact or Fiction. October 8-10, 1991
Fifteenth Annual Literary Festival: Words at Play, October 4-8, 1992
Sixteenth Annual Literary Festival, October 4-7, 1993
Seventeenth Annual Literary Festival: Cultural Equities, October 3-6, 1994
Eighteenth Annual Literary Festival: World Voice, October 3-5, 1995
Nineteenth Annual Literary Festival: Forbidden Passage, October 10-15, 1996
Twentieth Annual Literary Festival: Fierce Minds at Work, October 14-17, 1997
Twenty-first Annual Literary Festival: Electric Voice. Coming of Age, October 6-9, 1998
Twenty-second Annual Literary Festival: The Spirit of the Word, October 11-15, 1999
Twenty-third Annual Literary Festival: A New World, October 2-6, 2000
Twenty-fourth Annual Literary Festival: Magic, Vision, & Transformation, October 1-5, 2001
Twenty-fifth Annual Literary Festival: The Creative Moment, September 30 - October 5, 2002
Twenty-sixth Annual Literary Festival: Sounds that Mean, September 29-October 3, 2003
Scope and Content
This collection contains material from the Poetry Jam and first Literary Festival in 1978 and chronicles the annual Literary Festival onwards to the present day. Additional material is added yearly. Materials consist of original and digitized brochures, flyers, and promotional documents; schedules; news clippings; photos; and original and digitized video, as available.
Related Materials:
For further reference, please visit the Annual Literary Festival website at: http://www.lib.odu.edu/litfest/
This website contains digitized video, schedules, and additional information on Literary Festival speakers and directors.
Literary Festival display materials from a University Library display may be found in the Library Exhibit Archives in the Perry Library Special Collections.
Arrangement
The collection is sorted first by media type (i.e., printed materials, original video recordings, and digitized video) and then chronologically by year, date, and time.
Index Terms
Old Dominion University; Festivals--Virginia--Norfolk; Literature; Poetry
Contents List
- Brochures, Clippings, and Memorabilia 1977-
  - Printed Material 1977-
    Includes brochures and pamphlets, flyers, news clippings, metadata sheets for digitized materials, and other such printed materials.
    - Brochures 1977-1989 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Brochures 1990-1998 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Brochures 1999- (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Drawing 9 October 1991 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Metadata for Digitized Brochures and Photos (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Metadata for Digitized Video: 1st, 15th, and 18th Festivals (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Metadata for Digitized Video: 20th - 25th Festivals (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Metadata for Digitized Video: 26th - Festivals (Box-folder 1:8)
    - News Clippings, W. D. Snodgrass 1977-1978 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - News Clippings 1979-1980 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - 15th Annual Literary Festival 1992 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Poetry Jam I April 1978 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Poetry Jam II April 1978 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Poetry Jam April 1979 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Flyers (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Digitized Brochures and Photos on CD's 1978-2001
    Digitized brochures and photos in tiff and jpeg format stored on compact discs.
    - Literary Festival Photos, CD (Othertype 2:1)
    - Brochures 1978-1982, CD (Othertype 2:2)
    - Brochures 1983-1986, CD (Othertype 2:3)
    - Brochures 1987-1991, CD (Othertype 2:4)
    - Brochures 1992-1994, CD (Othertype 2:5)
    - 1995-1998, CD (Othertype 2:6)
    - 22nd Litfest brochure Tiffs 1999, CD (Othertype 2:7)
    - 23rd Litfest Brochure, and Photo Tiffs, and Author Jpegs 2000, CD (Othertype 2:8)
    - 24th Litfest Brochure, Photo, and Author Tiffs 2001, CD (Othertype 2:9)
- Video Tapes 1978-2002
  - 3/4 inch U-Matic Videocassettes 1978
    The original video from the 1st Annual Arts Reunion in 1978 was recorded on 3/4-inch U-Matic videocassettes. This sub-series is comprised of 10 of these tapes that have also been transferred to VHS tapes.
    - Anthony Hecht. Reading. 7:30 pm 25 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:1 of 10)
    - The Woman's Voice. Nancy Bazin, Linda Mizejewski, and Debra Bruce. 12:30 pm 26 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:2 of 10)
    - Translation Performance. Stelan Grunwald, Regula Meier, Abbot Sax, Benjamin Clymer. 12:00 pm 27 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:3 of 10)
    - Readings by W. D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 1 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:4 of 10)
    - Readings by W. D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 1 (repair tape) 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:5 of 10)
    - Readings by W. D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 2 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:6 of 10)
    - AWP Reading: Marvin Bell, Ellen Voigt, David Madden. 8:00 pm 28 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:7 of 10)
    - Jazz/Poetry Performance. Martin Pachey Quartet. 12:00 pm 29 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:8 of 10)
    - The Final Reunion, Now and Then AWP Reading: Daniel Halpern, Charles Wright and Intermission. Part 1 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:9 of 10)
    - The Final Reunion, Now and Then AWP Reading: Daniel Halpern, Charles Wright and Intermission. Part 2 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, U-Matic (Othertype 3:10 of 10)
  - VHS-C Tapes 2000-2003
    The 23rd, 24th, and 26th Annual Literary Festivals were recorded in full or in part on VHS-C tapes. This sub-series may be appended, should future festivals be recorded in this format.
    - 23rd Annual Literary Festival 2000
      - MFA Faculty Reading. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Gary Short. 4:00 pm 6 October 2000, VHS-C (Othertype 4:1 of 1)
    - 24th Annual Literary Festival 2001
      - Roberly Bell. "Literary Festival Preview. September 30, 2001. 2:30pm. And Terry Perrel, Temple West, and Tom Yuill Graduates of ODU's MFA program. October 1, 2001. 4pm. 2:30 pm 30 September 2001 and 4:00 pm 1 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:1 of 8)
      - Roseann Runte 8:00 pm 1 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:2 of 8)
      - Agymah Kamau. October 2, 2001. 2pm. And Tom Yuill continued from October 1, 2001. 4pm. 2:00 pm 2 October 2001 and 4:00 pm 1 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:3 of 8)
      - Sheryl St. Germain 4:00 pm 2 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:4 of 8)
      - Eugene Gloria 4:00 pm 3 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:5 of 8)
      - Joseph Skibell 4:00 pm 4 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:6 of 8)
      - Greg Bottoms 2:00 pm 5 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:7 of 8)
      - Karen McElmurray 4:00 pm 5 October 2001, VHS-C (Othertype 4:8 of 8)
    - Annual Literary Festival 2003
      - Rhoda Stamell 2:00 pm 30 September 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:1 of 6)
      - Jamie Callan 8:00 pm 30 September 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:2 of 6)
      - Paul Miller, a.k.a. DJ Spooky that Subliminal Kid 12:00 pm 1 October 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:3 of 6)
      - Rick Skwiot 10:00 pm 2 October 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:4 of 6)
      - Marilyn Chin 11:00 pm 3 October 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:5 of 6)
      - Peter Meinke 3:00 pm 3 October 2003, VHS-C (Othertype 4:6 of 6)
  - VHS Tapes 1978-2002
    Video from many of the Literary Festivals has been recorded in VHS format - either originally or the video has been migrated to this media format. There are notable gaps as not all Festivals were recorded; not all speakers were recorded for Festivals that were video taped; and some years were recorded using a different media type and not VHS. This sub-series may be appended, should future festivals be recorded in this format.
    - 1st Annual Arts Reunion 1978
      - Anthony Hecht. Reading 7:30 pm 25 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:1 of 10)
      - The Woman's Voice. Nancy Bazin, Linda Mizejewski, and Debra Bruce 12:30 pm 26 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:2 of 10)
      - Translation Performance. Stelan Grunwald, Regula Meier, Abbot Sax, and Benjamin Clymer 12:00 pm 27 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:3 of 10)
      - Readings by W.D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 1 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:4 of 10)
      - Readings by W.D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 1 -- repair tape 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:5 of 10)
      - Readings by W.D. Snodgrass. And The Fuhrer Banker staged by Paul Dicklin. Part 2 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:6 of 10)
      - AWP Reading: Marvin Bell, Ellen Voigt, David Madden 8:00 pm 28 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:7 of 10)
      - Jazz/Poetry Performance. Martin Pachey Quartet 12:00 pm 29 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:8 of 10)
      - The Final Reunion, Now and Then AWP Reading: Daniel Halpern, Charles Wright and Intermission. Part 1 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:9 of 10)
      - The Final Reunion, Now and Then AWP Reading: Daniel Halpern, Charles Wright and Intermission. Part 2 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, VHS (Othertype 5:10 of 10)
    - 15th Annual Literary Festival 1992
      - Who All Killed Cock Robin? A play by William Patrick. Adapted by W.D. Snodgrass and DeLoss McGraw 7:30 pm 4 October 1992, VHS (Othertype 5:1 of 5)
      - Words at Play: A Panel Performance on Childhood and Literature. Jean Fritz, Jay O'Callahan, W.D. Snodgrass, Fred Chappell, and Kathryn Morton 6:00 am 6 October 1992, VHS (Othertype 5:2 of 5)
      - A Staged Reading of Reverse Thunder: A Dramatic Poem by Diane Ackerman. And Paul West: Fiction Reading from The women of Whitechapel and Jack the Ripper 7:30 pm 6 October 1992, VHS (Othertype 6:3 of 5)
      - W.D. Snodgrass & Kathy Snodgrass: Poetry Reading and Slideshow from W.D.'s Midnight Carnival. And Jay O'Callahan: The Art of Storytelling 11:00 am 7 October 1992, VHS (Othertype 6:4 of 5)
      - Charles Johnson: Fiction Reading. And John Toomey: Original Jazz Performance 7:30 pm 8 October 1992, VHS (Othertype 6:5 of 5)
    - 18th Annual Literary Festival 1995
      - Intro by M. Evelina Galang. Synthesis Motion Theater. Fiction Reading by Fiona Cheong. October 3, 1995. 11am. And Poetry Reading by Quraysh Ali. October 3, 1995. 1pm. 11:00 am 3 October 1995 and 1:00 pm 3 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:1 of 6)
      - Panel Discussion: When Political Struggle in Literature Stops Being Literature. Dana Heller, Agha Shahid Ali, Quraysh Ali, Eavan Boland 3:00 pm 3 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:2 of 6)
      - Melody Ruffin Ward and Elbert Watson: Dance: Hymn for the Fainthearted. October 3, 1995. 7:45pm. Poetry Reading by Eavan Boland. October 3, 1995. 8pm. Poetry Reading by Tim Seibles. October 4, 1995. 11am. 7:45 pm 3 October 1995, 8:00 pm 3 October 1995, and 11:00 am 4 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:3 of 6)
      - Poetry Reading by Agha Shahid Ali. October 4, 1995. 3pm. Music: Agnes Fuller Song to the Moon. October 4, 1995. 7:45pm. Fiction Reading by Ninotchka Rosca. October 4, 1995. 8pm 3:00 pm 3 October 1995, 7:45 pm 4 October 1995, and 8:00 pm 4 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:4 of 6)
      - Poetry Reading by Mary Crow. October 5, 1995. 11am. Silencing of Women: Direct and Indirect Censorship, Ninotchka Rosca. October 5, 1995. 3pm 11:00 am 5 October 1995 and 3:00 pm 5 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:5 of 6)
      - Welcoming and Thanks by M. Evelina Galang. Illocano Dance Troupe. October 5, 1995. 7:45pm. Fiction Reading by Ariel Dorfman. October 5, 1995. 8pm 7:45 pm 5 October 1995 and 8:00 pm 5 October 1995, VHS (Othertype 6:6 of 6)
    - 20th Annual Literary Festival 1997
      - Cornelius Eady. Poetry 10:00 am 14 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 6:1 of 9)
      - Panel Discussion: The Inner Mounting Flame: Self, Culture, and Witness. Cornelius Eady and Joy Harjo 1:30 pm 14 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 6:2 of 9)
      - Melissa Fay Greene. Non-Fiction 3:00 pm 14 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 6:3 of 9)
      - Mike D'Orso: Journalism and Non-fiction. 10am. And Poetry Reading by Liz Waldner. October 15, 1997. 2pm 10:00 am 15 October 1997 and 2:00 pm 15 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:4 of 9)
      - Panel Discussion: What Kind of Fire: Three Genres, Three Truths? Liz Waldner, Reginald McKnight, and Melissa Fay Greene. October 15, 1997. 3:30pm. And Fiction Reading by Reginald McKnight. October 15, 1997. 7:30pm 3:30 pm 15 October 1997 and 7:30 pm 15 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:5 of 9)
      - A Conversation with Martin Espada: Race, Culture, Rage and Compassion 2:00 pm 16 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:6 of 9)
      - Martin Espada. Poetry Reading. October 16, 1997. 8pm. And Poetry Reading by Marita Golden. October 17, 1997. 10am 8:00 pm 16 October 1997 and 10:00 am 17 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:7 of 9)
      - Fiction by Richard Hell. October 17, 1997. 2pm. And Panel Discussion Friction: The Rub Between Fiction and Non-Fiction. Richard Hell, Gay Talese, Mike D'Orso, Louise Redd. October 17, 1997. 3:30pm 2:00 pm 17 October 1997 and 3:30 pm 17 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:8 of 9)
      - Gay Telese. Recital 8:00 pm 17 October 1997 and 3:30 pm 17 October 1997, VHS (Othertype 7:9 of 9)
    - 21st Annual Literary Festival 1998
      - Tony Grooms. Fiction and Poetry. October 6, 1998. 2pm. And Jane Bernstein. Non-fiction. October 6, 1998. 3:30pm 2:00 pm 6 October 1998 and 3:30 pm 6 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:1 of 11)
      - Robert Pinsky 8:00 pm 6 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:2 of 11)
      - Jacqueline Woodson. Fiction 10:00 am 7 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:3 of 11)
      - Jack Myers. Poetry. October 7, 1998. 2pm. And Panel Discussion Saying What You Mean: The Art of Honesty. Jack Myers and Jacqueline Woodson. October 7, 1998. 3:30pm 2:00 pm 7 October 1998 and 3:30 pm 7 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:4 of 11)
      - Nicole Brossard. Poetry, Fiction, and Non-fiction 8:00 pm 7 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:5 of 11)
      - Scott Cairns. Poetry. And Open Mike.10:00 am 8 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 7:6 of 11)
      - Tony Hoagland. Poetry. October 8, 1998. 2pm. And Panel Discussion A New Dialogue: Asian and Asian-American Writers in America. Li-Young Lee and Maria Luisa Carino. October 8, 1998. 3:30pm 2:00 pm 8 October 1998 and 3:30 pm 8 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 8:7 of 11)
      - Li-Young Lee. Poetry 8:00 pm 8 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 8:8 of 11)
      - Panel Discussion Who Do You Believe? Three Genres, Three Takes? Tony Hoagland, Sena Naslund, and Michael Pearson 10:00 am 9 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 8:9 of 11)
      - Sena Naslund. Fiction 2:00 pm 9 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 8:10 of 11)
      - John McPhee. Non-fiction 8:00 pm 9 October 1998, VHS (Othertype 8:11 of 11)
    - 22nd Annual Literary Festival 1999
      - Rita Dove Final Event (with Philip Raisor, Mike Pearson, Gary Short). Transcribed March 1, 2000 8:00 pm 15 October 1999, VHS (Othertype 8:1 of 1)
    - 23rd Annual Literary Festival 2000
      - Tim O'Brien 8:00 pm 3 October 2000, VHS (Othertype 8:1 of 2)
      - MFA Faculty Reading. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Gary Short 4:00 pm 6 October 2000, VHS (Othertype 8:2 of 2)
    - 24th Annual Literary Festival 2001
      - Holly Hughes 8:00 pm 2 October 2001, VHS (Othertype 8:1 of 3)
      - Margorie Agosin 8:00 pm 2 October 2001, VHS (Othertype 8:2 of 3)
      - Dorothy Allison 8:00 pm 5 October 2001, VHS (Othertype 8:3 of 3)
    - 25th Annual Literary Festival 2002
      - The Breathing Word: Promotional Video for the Annual Literary Festival 2002 August 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:1 of 15)
      - Writing Women's Voices. Debra Bruce and Lenore Hart 2:00 pm 30 September 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:2 of 15)
      - The Round Square: Readings in a Fluid Box. Luisa Igloria, Michael Pearson, Janet Peery, Sheri Reynolds, Tim Seibles, and Brian Silberman 8:00 pm 30 September 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:3 of 15)
      - Poem as Community, Community as Poem. Universes - Gamel Abdel Chasten, Lemon, Flaco Navaja, Steven Sapp, and Mildred Ruiz 12:30 pm 1 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:4 of 15)
      - Readings Across the Color Lines. Wanda Coleman and Gregory H. Williams 8:00 pm 1 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:5 of 15)
      - Creative Non-fiction. The Prismatic Genre. David Fenza, Philip Gerard, and Valerie Miner 11:00 am 2 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:6 of 15)
      - An Association of Readers. Allison Joseph, Pablo Medina, and Mark Winegardner 2:00 pm 2 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:7 of 15)
      - An Evening of Translation and Performance. W.D. Snodgrass, Steve Kelley, Frederick Lubich, Marilyn Marloff, Agnes Mobley-Wynne, Peter Schulman, and Lee Teply 8:00 pm 2 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:8 of 15)
      - Re-reading the Literary Festival. Evelina Galang, William B. Patrick, Peggy Shumaker, and Wayne Ude 11:00 am 3 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:9 of 15)
      - Forging the Individual Mind. Mark Doty 2:00 pm 3 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:10 of 15)
      - President's Lecture Series. Susan Sontag 8:00 pm 3 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:11 of 15)
      - Given that the Painter is a Poet, the Poet a Painter. Mark Doty, W.D. Snodgrass, Donald Roller Wilson, and Linda McGreevy 11:00 am 4 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:12 of 15)
      - Reinventing Nature. Barbara Hurd, Robert Richardson, Marjorie Sandor, and Tom Robotham 2:00 pm 4 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 9:13 of 15)
      - Virginia Deep in the Bones. R.H.W. Dillard, George Garrett, Henry Taylor, and Ellen Bryant Voigt 8:00 pm 4 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 10:14 of 15)
      - A Final Celebration. Stephen Dunn 8:00 pm 5 October 2002, VHS (Othertype 10:15 of 15)
- Digitized Video 1978-2003
  - Compact Discs (CD's) 1978-2003
    Compact discs are the most common storage method for digitized video from the Festivals. As such, there are compact discs for virtually every year of the festival that were recorded. This sub-series may be appended, should digitized video from future festivals be stored in this media format.
    - 1st Annual Arts Reunion 1978
      - An Interview with W.D. Snodgrass by Michael McLane 24 January 1979, CD (Othertype 11:1 of 8)
      - Reading by Anthony Hecht 7:30 pm 25 January 1978, CD (Othertype 11:2 of 8)
      - Reading the Women's Voice. Nancy Bazin, Linda Mizejewski, and Debra Bruce. September 26, 1978. 12:30pm; AWP Reading. Marvin Bell, Ellen Voigt, & David Madden. September 28, 1978. 8pm 12:30 pm 26 September 1978 and 8:00 pm 28 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:3 of 8)
      - Reading by W.D. Snodgras 8:00 pm 27 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:4 of 8)
      - Translation Performance. Stelan Grunwald, Regula Meier, Abbot Sax, Benjamin Clymer, and Hope Mihalap. September 27, 1978. 12pm; AWP Reading: Ellen Voigt. September 28, 1978. 8pm 12:00 pm 27 September 1978 and 8:00 pm 28 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:5 of 8)
      - AWP Reading. Marvin Bell, Ellen Voigt, and David Madden. September 28, 1978. 8pm; The Final Reunion: Now and Then. Charles Wright. September 29, 1978. 7:30pm 9:00 pm 28 September 1978 and 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:6 of 8)
      - Jazz / Poetry Performance. Martin Pachey Quartet 12:00 pm 29 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:7 of 8)
      - Reading by Anthony Hecht. September 25, 1978. 7:30pm; AWP Reading. William Matthews. September 27, 1978. 2pm; Poetry Quartet. September 29, 1978. 7:30pm; The Final Reunion: Now and Then. Daniel Halpern. September 29, 1978. 7:30pm 7:30 pm 25 September 1978, 2:00 pm 27 September 1978, and 7:30 pm 29 September 1978, CD (Othertype 11:8 of 8)